# **Chirag K. Deotare**

New State Bank Colony Nagpur Road Wardha -442001 Maharashtra



1

9970466721, 7972696769

#### **About Me**

# **Manufacturing and Operations Professional**

A high performing Manufacturing and Operations professional with an outstanding record of successfully handling challenging situations. Currently working in Whirlpool of India Pvt. Ltd (Manufacturing). With around 6 years of experience, handling hard core Engineering, Production field, coupled with excellent exposure of the industrial engg and have effectively propelled the organizations towards growth, strong transitioning and successful functional units.

### **Work Experience**

Sept 2018 – Current Sr. Executive (Manufacturing) Whirlpool of India Ranjangaon, Pune, Maharashtra

Whirlpool Corporation is consistently recognized by Fortune Magazine as one of the World's Most Admired Companies. Our values are the driving force behind everything we do. Respect, integrity, diversity and inclusion, teamwork and the spirit of winning propel our teams to excellence. Get to know us and see what it's like to be part of the world's leading major home appliance company.

- \*Follow up production plans and execution of the production targets, Meeting On-Time Delivery Process control
- Identify loss reduction projects based on WCM Cost Deployment, Quality, and Safety matrices.
- ♣ Stratify losses to prioritize and select proper tools to reduce losses
- ♣ Working as core team members in proper methodologies and tool usage to attack losses (Focused Improvement, Workplace Organization, Autonomous Maintenance, Safety)
- Work with cross-functional teams in identifying the root cause of problems and lead team in loss reduction projects.
- Design and deploy efficient material handling and material flow.
- Manpower handling
- Working on WCM concepts

April 2017 – Sept 2018 Team Member (Operation) Saint Gobain Sekurit India Chakan, Pune, Maharashtra

Saint-Gobain Sekurit supplies automotive glazing and modular components for the global vehicle manufacturing segment and the replacement market Saint-Gobain Sekurit India Ltd (SGSIL) is the Indian subsidiary of Saint-Gobain Sekurit France. Sekurit India has two manufacturing plant located near Pune - at Chakan for laminated windshields and at Bhosari for tempered side and back glasses.

- ♣Follow up production plans and execution of the production targets, Meeting On-Time Delivery Process control
- ♣ Quality control in production line, Reduction of rejection, wastage/scrap through 7QC tools, Root cause analysis/ Data Collection/Corrective action
- Preparation of production charts and reports
- ♣ Training of the operators –Casuals
- A Record wastage, rejects & scraps
- Manpower handling
- \* TS, ISO, OHSAS Documentation
- Initiate and drive productivity and quality improvement initiatives
- Working on WCM concepts

July 2014 – April 2017 **Sr. Production Engg** APL Apollo Tubes Ltd.

Murbad, Maharashtra

APL Apollo Tubes Limited is the largest producer of Electric Resistance Welded (ERW) steel pipes including one of the largest section pipe & tube manufacturers in India, with a capacity to produce more than 1.3 million tons per annum. It caters extensively to the region and exports to over 20 countries globally. The company's vast distribution network is spread across India, having warehouses and branch offices in 25 cities, making it one of the leading Galvanised Iron (GI) pipe manufacturers in India.

- A SAP (Production Planning) team leader. Managing daily production planning
- A Plan and coordinate production engineering processes on daily basis to produce high
- ♣ quality products. Develop process improvements to effectively utilize equipment and materials to
- Maximize production.
- \* Establish safety procedures and environmental regulations for employees.

May 2013 – April 2014 **PG Project Trainee** GM India Pvt. Ltd Pune Pune. Maharashtra

- ♣ Improvement in Productivity by Reducing Diagnostic Trouble Cause (DTC) which results into drastic reduction in downtime, operators efforts, and cost.
- ♣ Analyse and Improvement in Ergonomics issue related to Card Handle which intern gives a drastically reduction in human effort and work satisfaction.
- ♣ Waste Elimination in Hot Test with the help of Kaizen techniques
- Engine Head Sub-assembly Key-up station First Time Quality (FTQ) improvement by means of implementation of new manual tool.
- ♣ Tappet Line FTQ improvement by implementation of troubleshooting.
- ♣ Commissioning of New Hot Test Cell 3 and planning for new hot test cell layout and successfully implementation of new layout.

# **Education**

Masters, Mechanical (Production) Engg.Graduated, June 2014Walchand College of Engg, SangliMarks 7.92 CGPIAutonomous InstituteDivision A

Sangli, Maharashtra

Bachelor, Mechanical Engg. Graduated, July 2011

BDCOE, Sevagram Marks 65.2%
Nagpur University Board Division 1
Wardha, Maharashtra

**10+2** Passed, July 2007

New English Jr. College Marks 73% State Board Division 1

# **Computer Proficiency**

Word 2010

• Excel 2010

Power Point 2010

Wardha, Maharashtra

# Languages

Marathi

• Hindi

• English

#### **Personal Details**

Father's Name: Mr. Kishor Deotare Marital Status: Single Birthday: June 25, 1990 Nationality: Indian

Gender: Male

#### **Declaration**

I, Chirag Deotare, hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

\_\_\_\_\_Chirag Deotare